Venus Project
金星計畫
is an unusually large project to terraform Venus
那是利用來訪者的超科技
under the leadership of the Planetary Development Corporation,
在行星開發公團的主導下
using the Visitors' super technology.
將金星地球化的龐大計畫
Venus now
現在的金星
has the cloud plant in its atmosphere
在大氣層內設有造雲設備
that changes the structure of its atmosphere,
改變其大氣結構
transforming the environment into one suitable for carbon-based life forms.
正在將地表改造成 適合碳基生物生存的環境
Meanwhile,
於此同時
12 artificial black holes are being used to control gravity,
利用12台人工黑洞 所進行的重力控制
slowly moving the Venus towards the orbit with a rotation similar to Earth's.
將整個金星慢慢向 與地球相同的自轉軌道上移動
Many Neans are manufactured here,
眾多的涅安在這裡出廠
and they engage in terraforming Venus.
從事這個地球化作業
At such a huge cost,
為何要不惜如此
who is this new habitable space for?
這又是為了誰 所準備的新的舒適空間呢
Its true purpose is still unknown.
其真正目的未尚讓人知曉
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
Come in.
進來
Deputy Director Junghardt.
容格哈特次長
No, you are already the former Deputy Director.
不對 已經是前次長了
As you used the Proto-Nean to take actions without permission,
根據你私自運用原形涅安 進行行動的事實
the Ochrona demands the immediate dissolution of the Aletheia.
守護局要求真理部立即解散
Even I, the deity officer, cannot overturn this decision.
這項決定 連我這個神祇官都無法改變
The Ochrona has long wanted to bypass the Aletheia,
守護局從以前就很想擁有
and it has direct access to the Visitors.
不透過真理局 直接跟來訪者交涉的權限
It gives them an excuse.
這正好給了他們一個藉口
Then…
那麼…
Did you leak the news?
是妳走漏這個風聲的嗎
You are very special.
妳很特別
So, I also anticipated this risk.
所以我也猜到會有這種風險
You gave it to me when knowing the risks?
明知有風險還交給我嗎
I let you be my subordinate and stay with Rouge.
讓妳成為我的部下 跟在露瓊身邊
So,
那麼…
do you want to ask me something?
妳是想要來向我問什麼嗎
Then let me just cut to the chase.
那我就開門見山地說了
I met that Puppetmaster you were secretly investigating
我在那個移動嘉年華裡所遇到
at the traveling carnival earlier.
那個你也在秘密調查的操偶師
Who exactly is he?
他到底是什麼人
The secret investigation hasn't ended yet.
秘密調查還沒有結果
I had agents track him down,
我讓特務去追查他的下落
CERES but they lost him around Ceres.
(谷神星) 但在谷神星一帶就跟丟了
Is he a Usurper?
是簒奪者嗎
Or is he a human being who assists the Usurpers?
還是說人類裡有人在協助他
Or did he let us think that he wants to join the Usurpers in the inviolable line,
又或者是讓我們以為 他要在不可侵界線裡跟簒奪者會合
VENUS but in fact his target is here?
(金星) 實際上的目標是這裡呢
The Venus Project?
金星計畫嗎
For this project, Venus has black reactors that can produce micro black holes,
為了這個計畫 金星上有著 可產生小形黑洞的黑色反應爐
and this is also the largest manufacturing base of Nean.
而且這裡還是涅安的最大製造據點
If that was the case, it would be complicated.
若真是這樣 情況就會很複雜
The gears seem to be starting to deviate.
齒輪好像開始偏了
It is necessary to adjust them before they completely deviate.
有必要在完全偏離前進行調整
That Puppetmaster interfered with Rouge's memory.
操偶師干涉了露瓊的記憶
Let me ask you.
我問你
Is there something you're hiding from us about the kid?
關於那個孩子 你是不是還有東西瞞著我們
No matter what,
無論如何
since her true identity has been revealed,
既然她的真實身分已經曝光
Rouge Redstar will be transferred to the Ochrona.
露瓊・雷德斯塔 將會被移送至守護局
She will receive appropriate punishment there.
在那裡被施以適當的處分
Appropriate punishment?
適當的處分
That's your favorite word.
是你們最愛的用詞
There's no appropriate punishment at all.
什麼狗屁"適當的處分"
They removed me from the Junghardt murder case.
居然把我調離容格哈特被殺案
Someone must have done something on it.
這肯定是因為來自某個地方的壓力
You've submitted many false documents and done unauthorized searches before.
你接受過很多針對提交偽造資料 以及擅自搜查的處分
I think this is a reasonable and appropriate punishment.
我認為這是 極為合理的且適當的裁決
Whose side are you on anyway?
你到是站在誰那邊的
Of course, I'm on your side.
當然是你
Where are we going next?
接下來我們要去哪裡
We're going to the Aletheia.
去真理部
I heard that the red suspect was captured.
那個紅色嫌犯被抓了起來
How can I just sit by and do nothing?
我怎麼能就這樣坐視不管
We are not gears for the organization.
我們可不是組織的齒輪
Rouge Redstar, is she really that red suspect?
露瓊・雷德斯塔 真的就是那名紅色嫌犯嗎
Yes, I saw it with my own eyes.
是啊 我親眼看見了
It can't be wrong.
不會錯的
But as the Aletheia is now under the control of the Ochrona,
但是真理部在守護局的管理之下
I don't think they will help us.
我不認為他們會協助我們
Not to mention it's not our case anymore.
更別說這已經不是我們的案子…
I don't care.
我管他那麼多
I'm going straight in.
正面對決
Everything will be fine in the end.
船到橋頭自然直
You are too casual in your actions.
太隨便了吧
You are a lover of murmur.
你真的很愛碎唸
That's why I hate Neans.
所以我才討厭涅安
I need Nectar more than chocolate now.
比起巧克力 現在更需要涅克托呢
This case has violated Article 5 of the Artificial Species Utilization Regulation.
這次的案子牴觸了 人造種運用規定第5條
We determined it to be the private act of Gene Junghardt.
斷定為吉恩・容格哈特的私自行為
You will be held accountable for your leadership as Minister of Aletheia,
在追究妳身為真理部部長 的管理責任的同時
and this case is a clear overreach for the Aletheia,
對於沒有搜查權的真理部而言
which has no search authority.
這是明顯的越權行為
I understand.
我明白
So what does the Ochrona want to do with the Aletheia?
那麼守護局想要怎麼處置真理部
We have asked the Health and Welfare Ethics Committee to disband the Aletheia,
我們已向人造種厚生論理委員會 提出解散真理部的要求
of course, and to remove you from your position as Minister.
當然也要解除妳這個部長職位
Minister Zhao.
趙部長
I'm sorry.
很遺憾
Your application cannot be submitted without the approval from me, the deity officer.
沒有我這位神祇官的同意 你們的申請是無法上呈至委員會的
But…
可是…
Only I, the Deity Officer, have the power
能使行同意權的人只有神祇官
to give consent.
也就是本人我
You're Herman Heyward, executive director of Panacea Corporation, right?
我記得你是萬靈企業的執行董事 赫爾曼・霍華德對吧
Why are you here since you are a civilian?
為什麼身為平民的你會在這裡
I'm here to help with that Proto-Nean case,
我會來這裡
that is, the Rouge Redstar case.
是為了協助處理那個原形涅安 也就是露瓊・雷德斯塔的案子
I heard she can deform into combat mode
聽說她能夠像那些不朽者一樣
like the Immortals.
變形為戰鬥形態之類的
What's that called?
那個叫什麼來著…
I remember it's…
我記得是…
Code name is Metal Rouge, so?
代號 鋼鐵露瓊 是嗎
Because she's a precious specimen.
因為她是極其珍貴的樣品
We hope to disassemble her and conduct a thorough investigation.
站在本公司的立場 希望能讓我們將她解體並徹底調查
After the investigation is over,
待調查結束後
our company will take responsibility to dispose of her.
本公司會負起責任 將其處分掉
Rouge Redstar is now under the control of the Aletheia.
露瓊・雷德斯塔 現在歸屬於真理部的管理之下
I can't give her to you without appropriate application.
只要沒有經過正規手續申請 就不能交給你
In this situation, do I still care what you say?
現在是講管理這種話的時候嗎
We can't allow a dangerous person be protected by an organization that violates its rules.
我們不可能放任這種危險人物 被違反規約的組織所保護
Whether she is dangerous or not is judged by me, the deity officer,
是否危險 是由我這個神祇官來做判斷
not you.
並不是你
That's because you didn't see it,
那是因為妳沒看到
so you could say such things.
才能說出這種話來
As soon as you see the hole that guy made in Sarah's chest,
只要看到那個傢伙 在莎拉胸口開出的大洞
you'll…
妳也會…
Is the Sarah you mentioned that Sarah Fitzgerald?
你口中的莎拉 是指莎拉・費茲傑羅
One of the Immortal Nine, Purgatory Viola, right?
也就是不朽九人之一 煉獄的拜歐拉對吧
Are you close to her?
請問你們是有什麼深切的關係嗎
Then please leave.
那麼 請回吧
I think she's almost out of Nectar.
涅克托差不多快沒了吧
Should I ask the higher-ups if she needs an injection?
要跟上頭問一下是否要注射嗎
NO SIGNAL What?
(無訊號) 咦
Hey, what's going on?
喂 這是怎麼回事
NO SIGNAL Make a check now.
(無訊號) 快點檢查
Y-Yes.
是…是的
Alright, let's get out of here.
好了 我們離開這裡
What?
咦
You look like Jill.
妳看起像是吉兒
Is it my illusion?
是我的幻覺嗎
I am the real one.
我是本尊
How did you get in?
妳是怎麼進來的
It's my Nean friend who helped me.
是我的涅安朋友幫忙牽線的
Do you make friends with Neans?
吉兒本尊跟涅安是朋友嗎
Because I am also a Nean.
因為我也是涅安啊
Nean… Miss Jill.
涅安的…吉兒小姐
What?
咦
You like this, right?
妳喜歡這個對吧
Do you want to eat it?
要吃嗎
With your agility, you could escape,
妳明明也有機會能逃脫的
why did you want to be arrested?
為什麼要乖乖被捕呢
This way.
往這邊
Who exactly
妳到底…
are you?
是何方神聖
Where is this place?
這裡是哪裡
What is this?
這個是什麼
Those Neans who are judged to be in danger would be brought into here.
這裡是被判斷有危險的涅安們 會被帶來的地方
Some will be disassembled.
有的會被解體
Others will be…
有的則是…
Everyone is well-preserved.
大家都保存得很好呢
Those who commit crimes will be brought to justice.
犯罪的人會接受法律審判
But we can only be disposed of.
但我們只能單方面被處分掉
Just because we want to live freely.
只因為我們想自由地活下去
Jill, are you one of the Immortal Nine?
吉兒…妳也是不朽九人嗎
Yes.
嗯…
This is a good look.
很漂亮的臉蛋
Why did you save me?
為什麼要救我呢
Because we need you.
因為我們需要妳
We Alters fight for freeing the Neans.
我們"奧塔" 是為了解放全涅安而戰的
Free?
解放…
To be free from the Asimov Code.
從阿茲莫夫代碼中解放
To be free from Nectar,
從涅克托中解放
and the curse from humans.
也從人類的詛咒中解放
I've told you.
我說過了
Freedom is the ability to make your own choices.
自由就是得自己做出選擇
The Asimov Code cannot be deleted.
阿茲莫夫代碼是無法刪除的
How could you free Neans…
是要怎麼解放涅安…
Yes, we can.
可以的
You can do that.
妳能做到那種事
You are pathetic.
真是可憐…
Gene never tells you anything about you, right?
吉恩完全沒告訴過妳 妳是個什麼樣的存在對吧
Gene…
吉恩他…
My brother only told me…
哥哥他只有對我說…
Your brother,
妳的哥哥…
Gene Junghardt has no long been the Deputy Director of the Aletheia.
吉恩・容格哈特 已經被解除真理部次長一職
You and your brother are just gears in the organization.
妳跟妳的哥哥 都只是組織裡的一顆齒輪
If the gears don't work,
如果運轉不順的話
new gears must be put in place,
就只能換上新的齒輪
then the old gears will be discarded.
然後捨棄掉
So…
所以…
The Proto-Nean has escaped from custody.
收押中的原形捏安逃跑了
The Fuenril squad is headed to capture Rouge Redstar on the run.
芬里爾小隊前往抓捕 逃走中的露瓊・雷德斯塔
They are my loyal men of war.
那是聽命於我的戰爭之犬
(Episode 7: Appropriate Gear)
(7 正確的齒輪)
To conquer or to die.
豁出去吧
IDENTIFICATION FAILED
(證認失敗)
You will die.
豁不出去呢
Warning.
警告…
An intruder appeared at gate 7B.
7B閘門處出現入侵者
Security personnel please handle it immediately.
請警衛人員立刻前往
Repeat.
重複一次…
Warning.
警告…
-This way. -An intruder appeared at gate 7B.
-往這邊 -7B閘門處出現入侵者
Security personnel please handle it immediately.
請警衛人員立刻前往
Repeat.
重複一次…
Warning.
警告…
An intruder appeared at gate 7B.
7B閘門處出現入侵者
Security personnel please handle it immediately.
請警衛人員立刻前往
Sorry.
抱歉
It's okay.
沒關係…
This is
這是我…
a decision I made myself.
我自己做出的決定…
Neans must not harm humans,
涅安不得加害於人類
and
以及…
must not ignore humans in danger.
不得對陷入危機的人類視而不見
Exactly.
沒錯
This is the death given by Asimov Code.
這是阿茲莫夫代碼所賜與的死亡
These are the creators…
這就是那群造物主…
This is what humans have given us.
這就是人類給予我們的東西
It's so disgusting.
令人作嘔
I want to give those creators who gave us a hard time…
要給斷罪於我們的造物主
I will give those humans punishment.
賜與人類懲罰
Compared to retrieving id from companions,
比起回收同伴的伊德
your rescue is more important to me.
我更重視對妳的營救
This is also due to my naivete.
這也是我的天真所致
It turns out to be just some cyborgs.
我還以是什麼人 居然是生化人傭兵之流
Quite clever.
挺聰明的嘛
Rouge.
露瓊
Naomi.
直美…
Why?
為什麼啊
Found her.
找到了
Look, she's here.
你看 果然在這裡…
Rouge.
露瓊
Why do you think we
妳覺得擁有如此力量的我們
have to submit to humans since we have such strong power?
為什麼非得屈居於人類之下
Flash Silvia.
閃光的希爾維雅
If you do not choose us,
要是無法與我們同行
then I have to destroy you.
那就只能毀了妳
Even the Double-Headed Aerkos is here.
連雙頭的亞格斯也來了…
Don't be slow. Get moving.
慢吞吞烏龜 快走吧
What?
咦
Lost the target.
失去目標
Go chase it.
趕緊去確認
-Understood. -Rescue the injured.
-瞭解 -救援傷患
Gears
齒輪…
gradually deviate.
逐漸偏掉了
You are also one of the Immortal Nine,
你也是不朽九人之一
Proto-Nean, right?
是原形涅安對吧
Why?
為什麼…
Alright, don't move.
好了 通通不要動
Oh my.
真是的
Red one, black one,
有紅色的又有黑色的
and a silver one.
剛剛才出現一個銀色的
What is it now?
現在又是什麼
Orange?
橘色的嗎
A child?
小孩子
No way, really?
不會吧 真的假的
Data shows
資料比對
that she appeared on the passenger list of the Mars shuttle.
她有出現在 火星聯絡船的乘客名單上
Are you Aes?
是艾斯嗎…
Are you really Aes?
真的是艾斯嗎
Do you want your eyes gouged out?
妳是想要眼珠子被挖掉嗎
What?
咦
Alice.
艾莉斯
I can't believe he wants me to save her.
居然要我來救這個傢伙
Aes is really naive.
艾斯果然是天真無邪啊
You are like a broken, abandoned cat.
簡直就像是破抹布般的棄養貓
I can't see what you could
完全看不出來能幫上我們…
help us.
什麼忙…
I'm sorry that Alice said something rude to you.
抱歉艾莉斯對妳說了失禮的話
Are you two the same person?
艾莉斯就是艾斯 艾斯其實是艾莉斯嗎
Well…
那個…
-She didn't really mean that. -Looks like a personality switch
-她其實不是那個意思 -看起來是種解離性同一性障礙
-What does she mean? -caused by dissociative identity disorder.
-哪是什麼意思 -所造成的人格切換
-Well… Cats are quite adorable. -Put it more simply.
-那個…貓咪不是很可愛嗎 -說簡單一點
-Yes, they are adorable. -It's multiple personalities.
-是很可愛啦 -就是多重人格
-So, Alice is… -I see.
-所以 艾莉斯她… -是喔
Rouge's secret…
露瓊的秘密…
ERROR Found defect in the security files of the Junghardt house.
(錯誤) 發現容格哈特宅邸保全資料有缺損
The Junghardt house?
容格宅邸
Display surveillance records.
顯示監控履歷
CARL LEONHARDT This is what you requested.
(卡爾・雷恩哈特) 這是您要求的東西
SPECTER JB7
(Specter JB7)
Rouge Redstar seems to have escaped from the Aletheia.
露瓊・雷德斯塔似乎逃出了真理部
Really?
是嗎…
What should we do next?
請問接下來要怎麼做
Of course,
當然是…
we need to get the gears back on track.
把齒輪導正了
Watch.
注視…
Speak up.
有話就說啦
Who said to cut down on smoking?
說要減少吸菸量的人是誰
Don't speak.
我的意思是叫你別說話
As one of the Immortal Nine,
身為不朽九人之一的你
why do you save me?
為什麼要救我呢
We've been running away from Silvia and the others.
我們一直都在逃離希爾維雅他們
Alice is amazing.
艾莉斯很厲害
She has access to the information and supplies we need to survive.
她能夠弄到 生存用的情報與必備物資
Thanks to Alice, we could keep running up to now.
多虧有艾莉斯 我們才能一直逃到今天
Alice was also the one who had information about the other Immortal Nine
掌握到不朽九人不斷遇害情報的人
being killed.
也是艾莉斯
And then I found out it's you, so I decided to approach you.
然後發現那個人就是露瓊 才決定接近妳
I'm against that, by the way.
順帶一提 我反對這麼做
What do you want me to do?
你們希望我做什麼
Unlike the other Immortal Nine,
我們與其他不朽九人不同
we just want to live a normal life.
只是想正常地活著
Rouge.
露瓊
Why do you have to hunt us down?
妳為什麼非得追殺我們不可呢
Because it's my mission.
因為這是任務
Can you kill anyone for the mission?
只要收到命令 妳誰都能殺嗎
Because Gene said you are dangerous.
因為吉恩說你們是危險人物…
We are not dangerous at all.
我們才不危險呢
She's just a killer who can't think.
這傢伙只是個不會思考的殺手
It's useless to say anything to her.
跟她說什麼都是沒用的
Aes, you're fine,
艾斯是還好
but Alice is like a villain.
但艾莉斯就有種壞蛋的感覺
Right.
是啊
I'm not that weak like Aes.
我跟艾斯不同 沒那麼軟弱
Don't you have any doubts about the missions you receive?
妳對接收到的命令 一點疑問也沒有嗎
Gene wouldn't tell me to do something wrong.
吉恩不會命令我去做錯的事
You've been mentioning Gene.
從剛剛開始 妳就東一句吉恩 西一句吉恩
How do you know that guy won't make mistakes?
妳又怎麼知道那傢伙不會有錯
What do you think?
妳自己又是怎麼想的
Are you guys good people or bad people?
你們到底是好人 還是壞人
You wanted to kill us, so are you a good person?
想要殺了我們的露瓊 是好人嗎
I…
我…
It's settled.
定案
You are a bad person.
妳是壞人
I am not. I am a good person.
我才不是壞人 我是好人
Can someone who wanted to kill us be a good person?
前來殺死我們的人 會是好人嗎
To us, Rouge, you're a really bad person.
對我們來說 露瓊 妳就是實實在在的壞人
Aes, you need to see the truth.
艾斯也快點搞清楚吧
We'd be fools to ask for help from someone like that.
我們就是笨 才會想要來依靠這種人的協助
Hey.
喂
Goodbye,
再見了
Miss "Good Person".
自稱好人的小姐
You are
我說妳啊…
really bad at communication.
真的很不會跟人交流欸
I see.
原來如此
So Roy Junghardt was killed by the Immortal Nine?
所以羅伊・容格哈特 是被不朽九人所殺的嗎
That's what Gene said.
吉恩是這樣說的
The Junghardt murder case investigation team
我們容格哈特殺害事件偵查組
is using this footage as a clue
以這段影像為線索
to keep track of you, the red suspect.
持續追查著妳這位紅色嫌犯
This is not me.
這個不是我
This could be the mimic Nean on the ship.
有可能是在聯絡船上的 那個能夠擬態的涅安
Right, Giallon.
沒錯 迦隆
That's him.
就是他
He said he did it too.
他也說是他殺的
But,
但是…
why would the Immortal Nine want to kill him?
不朽九人又為何要殺他
Giallon has already been killed by me.
迦隆已經被我殺掉了…
Dead men cannot give witness.
死無對證呢
I thought I would be dead.
還以為死定了
It's your luck if you could die.
還不如死了算了
Long time no see.
好久不見
Grauphon.
格勞芬